

Fatih Çalış

Nationality: Turkish Date of birth: 09/04/1992

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/fatihcaliss/

• Home: Kadıköy, 34000 İstanbul (Türkiye)

ABOUT ME

+3 year experienced in IT and an expert frontend developer, interested in writing codes, skilled at developing complex solutions, creating user friendly designs, excellent and dependable team player with strong analytical thinking skills. Quick to learn and adapt to new technologies, and create new solutions according to problems. Proven skills in problem solving, product life cycle, Frontend/Web Development specializing in ReactJS. As a dependable team player, I am dedicated to providing exceptional support and achieving goals through persistence, self-discipline, and reliability. It is recommended to review the github profile.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer

Fazla / Whole Surplus [12/03/2023 - 17/11/2023]

City: İstanbul **Country:** Türkiye

As a Frontend Developer at Fazla Gida/Whole Surplus in Istanbul, Turkey, I excelled in Nx monorepo projects, utilizing HTML, CSS, JavaScript ES6, Typescript, React.js, Next.js, and React Native. Proficient in Material UI, React functional components, and experienced in Unit and e2e testing. Skilled in Sentry.io for error tracking, Git for version control, and well-versed in SCRUM, Agile methodologies, and JIRA for effective project management.

Frontend Developer

Servicepark [10/03/2022 - 12/03/2023]

City: İstanbul
Country: Türkiye

As a Frontend Developer at Servicepark in Istanbul, Turkey, I specialized in HTML, CSS, JavaScript ES6, Typescript, and React. Proficient in React functional components and custom hooks, I developed applications using Typescript and Bootstrap. My expertise extends to Computational Thinking, Operating Systems, Linux, Version Control Systems (Git & Gitlab), and Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC). I successfully applied SCRUM & Agile methodologies, along with JIRA, to achieve optimal results in both individual and group projects.

Frontend Developer

Freelancer [01/04/2021 - 10/03/2022]

City: İstanbul **Country:** Türkiye

Worked according to customer requests. In this context, the technology stacks and designs used were selected and used in line with the customer's wishes; like HTML,CSS, SASS,Bootstrap and Javascript

PROJECTS

Fazla Market

[12/03/2023 - 17/12/2023]

As a Frontend Developer, I played a pivotal role in the creation of a high-performance commercial website using Next.js, Material-UI, and Tanstack Query. Leveraging the capabilities of Next.js, I implemented server-side

rendering for enhanced performance, while Material-UI components added a modern and cohesive design. The integration of Tanstack Query optimized data fetching and management, contributing to the overall responsiveness of the site. Through collaborative efforts with cross-functional teams, I ensured the seamless alignment of development with business goals.

Link: https://market.fazla.com

Fazla Portal

[12/03/2023 - 17/12/2023]

The management panel of the Fazla - https://apps.apple.com/tr/app/fazla/id1536386027?l=tr - app. Javascript, MaterialUI, ContextAPI, React Table, UnitTests/E2E Tests

Link: https://portal.fazla.com

Monitorpark

[12/03/2022 - 12/03/2023]

I designed and developed a cutting-edge B2B admin panel/dashboard platform leveraging React, TypeScript, Bootstrap, and GitLab for. This dynamic solution empowers users to effortlessly monitor and control their IT infrastructure with an intuitive interface, featuring specialized charts and a robust reporting section.

Esperanza Grup

[01/07/2021 - 15/08/2021]

In this project, I developed a single-page application that showcases the cafes owned by the client and the services they offer. With a focus on user-friendliness and engaging design, I worked diligently to create a customer-oriented solution.

Link: https://www.esperanzagrup.com.tr/

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Business and Systems Engineering (Bachelor's Degree)

National Defence University [31/07/2010 - 29/08/2014]

City: Ankara Country: Türkiye

Website: https://www.msu.edu.tr/

High School Graduate / Cadet

Kuleli Military High School [31/07/2006 - 09/07/2010]

City: İstanbul
Country: Türkiye

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Turkish

Other language(s):

English

LISTENING C1 READING C2 WRITING B2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION B2 SPOKEN INTERACTION B2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user